Liu Peng

"Where there is a will, there is a way"

Personal Profile

I received my Bachelor degree in Computer Science and Technology from the Hebei University of Technology (211), with awarded outstanding graduate. In my Bachelor thesis, I studied the generative model systematically, and used diffusion model for Chinese painting generation. I have read a lot of materials related to artificial intelligence, including books, blogs and papers, etc. I also have learnt many courses such as Stanford CS 231N for Computer Vision and CS 224N for Natural Language Processing, etc. Now, I am looking for a research assistant job (about 2 years) related to my research interests. I sincerely hope to have the opportunity do some meaningful work and publish papers on top conferences.

Research Interests

Generative Models, Multimodal, Foundation Model

Education_

Hebei University of Technology

Tianjin, China

August 2019 - June 2023

B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology, GPA 3.8/4

- Outstanding graduate of HEBUT
- Changed major to computer science and technology (Only two members)
- Turned down the opportunity for postgraduate recommendation
- A Member of Communist Party of China (CPC)

Work Experience

Scorching Stone Technology

Beijing, China

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

- Use diffusion model to genereate controllable e-commerce pictures.
- Locating and solving the problem of poor Chinese face generation.
- Locating and analyzing the blank background problem in inpainting mode.
- Change color for clothes.

Algorithms Engineer

Thesis

Generative Models Research and Chinese Painting Generation

Tianjin, China

Hebei University of Technology

Jan 2023 - June 2023

- Systematic learning of mainstream generative models
- Flow-based model, Autoregressive model, Energy-based model, VAE, Diffusion model, GAN
- Use diffusion model for Chinese painting generation
- Read a lot of materials

Skills

Programming Python (Pytorch, TensorFlow, PaddlePaddle, Scikit-Learn), C/C++, C#, Java, SQL, HTML, JavaScript, MATLAB

Miscellaneous Git, ET_FX, Markdown, Linux, Vim, Microsoft Office

Achievements

2023	Outstanding graduate of HEBUT, All aspects	Tianjin, China
2023	Innovation training program for college students, AI +Fiance, Leader, Province-level	Tianjin, China
2022	Entrepreneurship training program for college students, Software, Leader, Province-level	Tianjin, China
2021	First-class scholarship of Hebei University of Technology, Grades and extracurricular activities	Tianjin, China
2021	Merit student of Hebei University of Technology, All aspects	Tianjin, China
2020	First-class scholarship of Hebei University of Technology, Grades and extracurricular activities	Tianjin, China
2020	Merit student of Hebei University of Technology, All aspects	Tianjin, China

DECEMBER 7, 2023 1

Motivation

In a long run, I believe that the real artificial intelligence will come true, which will liberate productivity and enable people to live better lives. I would like to devote myself to the research on artificial intelligence.

Languages _

Chinese Native

English CET6, Proficient in reading

Advantages

Broaden Al Knowledge By learn lots of materials

Passion for AI I would like to devoted my self to artificial intelligence research

Solid theoretical foundation For some technology, I always want to explore the rationale behind it (My thesis is math heavy)

Thinking and reading skillsI have read lots of English books, papers etc. **Self-Motivation**Passionate about artificial intelligence

Have Learnt Courses

• Stanford CS 231N Deep Learning for Computer Vision, 2017 version and new content in 2023 version.

- Stanford CS 224N Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning, 2023 version
- MIT 6.S191 Introduction to Deep Learning
- Westlake Natural Language Processing Course in Spring 2023

Have Read Books

- Machine Learning (By Zhou Zhihua) (In Chinese)
- Statistical Learning Method (By Li Hang) (In Chinese)
- The Quest for Machine Learning (By Zhu Geyue, Calabash Brothers) (In Chinese)
- Hands-On Machine Learning with Scikit-Learn, Keras & TensorFlow (Aurélien Géron)
- Deep Learning with Python (By Francois Chollet) (Partially)
- Deep Learning with PyTorch (By Eli Stevens, Luca Antiga, Thomas Viehmann) (Partially)
- Computer Vision Algorithms and Applications (By Richard Szeliski)
- Generative Deep Learning (By David Foster) (Partially)
- Deep Learning (By Ian Goodfellow, Yoshua Bengio, and Aaron Courville)
- Deep Generative Modeling (By Jakub M. Tomczak)
- Natural Language Processing A Machine Learning Perspective (By Yue Zhang, Zhiyang Teng)
- Dive into Deep Learning (By Aston Zhang, Zack C. Lipton, Mu Li, and Alex J. Smola) (PyTorch Version)

Have read papers_

I have read dozens of papers about generative models, including diffusion series and gpt series. Here are some examples.

- 1. Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models
- 2. Denoising Diffusion Implicit Models
- 3. Diffusion Models Beat GANs on Image Synthesis
- 4. Deep unsupervised learning using nonequilibrium thermodynamics
- 5. Classifier-Free Diffusion Guidance
- 6. Diffusion Models: A Comprehensive Survey of Methods and Applications
- 7. Generative Modeling by Estimating Gradients of the Data Distribution
- 8. GLIDE: Towards Photorealistic Image Generation and Editing with Text-Guided Diffusion Models

DECEMBER 7, 2023 2

- 9. Hierarchical Text-Conditional Image Generation with CLIP Latents
- 10. High-Resolution Image Synthesis With Latent Diffusion Models
- 11. Improved Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models
- 12. Improved Techniques for Training Score-Based Generative Models
- 13. Palette: Image-to-Image Diffusion Models
- 14. RePaint: Inpainting using Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models
- 15. Score-Based Generative Modeling through Stochastic Differential Equations
- 16. SDEdit: Guided Image Synthesis and Editing with Stochastic Differential Equations
- 17. SDXL: Improving Latent Diffusion Models for High-Resolution Image Synthesis
- 18. U-Net: Convolutional Networks for Biomedical Image Segmentation
- 19. Attention is All you Need
- 20. BERT: Pre-training of Deep Bidirectional Transformers for Language Understanding
- 21. Improving Language Understanding by Generative Pre-Training
- 22. Language Models are Unsupervised Multitask Learners
- 23. Language Models are Few-Shot Learners
- 24. LoRA: Low-Rank Adaptation of Large Language Models
- 25. Scaling Laws for Neural Language Models
- 26. Learning Transferable Visual Models From Natural Language Supervision
- 27. On the Opportunities and Risks of Foundation Models
- 28. Segment Anything

DECEMBER 7, 2023 3